Rodolfo Ferreira

Sao Paulo, Brazil +55 13 91543167 rodolfo@rodolfoferreira.com.br http://rodolfoferreira.com.br/

Full-stack developer, open-source enthusiast. Loves building stuff that works.

I'm a programmer, problem solver and a big fusion and progressive music fan. I spend most of my non-working hours researching about various modern web development techniques, languages, platforms and paradigms.

Interest in building distributed web based services hosted in the cloud and planning/managing a cloud infrastructure.

Mission: prove that developing can be fun and users can be happy.

Technical Skills

Like: java, cloud, amazon-web-services, scala, clojure, javascript, git, github, gwt, playframework, hibernate,

jboss, puppet, mysql, node.js, npm, ruby, amazon-s3, maven, travis-ci, jenkins, mongodb, tdd, domain-

driven-design, jsf, rest, web-services, soap

Dislike: php, cakephp, .net, windows-server, sql-server

Experience

Web developer/engineer - Calango Music Instrumentos Musicais

August 2010 - August 2013

java, html5, css3, agile, javascript, web-services, rest, amazon-web-services, cakephp, apache, tomcat, netty, maven, tdd, hibernate, centos, spring-mvc, spring-ws

Developed experience in the PHP ecosystem, including Apache Server administration as well as database and cache APIs.

Responsible for engineering various new solutions using the Java Platform, specifically Java EE, including tools and frameworks such as Hibernate, Spring, JSF, GWT, Vaadin, VRaptor, JSTL, Log4j, Maven and Ant. Also worked in the front-end code, using pure HTML5 + JS or RIA frameworks such as jQuery, Underscore, Backbone, Socket.io. Used Node.js for some solutions envolving real-time processing and network programming.

Worked in a e-commerce environment, integrating with various APIs such as PayPal, Bradesco (Brazilian bank), Cielo (Brazilian credit card payments processor) and Cloud providers including Amazon Web Services, StormOnDemand, VPS.net, DreamHost (laaS) and Heroku, AppFog, AppEngine and, recently, Red Hat's Openshift (Paas). Also gained basic knowledge in cloud

Web Developer – Triares Sites e Software

January 2010 - June 2010

php, cakephp, html5, css, javascript, jquery, ubuntu, shared-hosting, flash, api

Responsible for developing web solutions for local clients, including websites, CRM, back office web systems. Worked in a very healthy team environment and developed skills in agile methodology and information architecture.

Following project timelines, most of my tasks were delivered ahead of time so I could use the remaining on planning and researching how could I best deliver the next one.

Helped many business get their web space up and running.

Education

B. S. Computer Science – FATEC Rubens Lara

2010 - 2012

Reviewed concepts learned in Technical Course and working experience, filling the gaps with academic knowledge wherever possible. Engaged in various topic discussion with teachers after class and student discussions to better improve understanding.

Gained academic background in the following topics: Algorithms, Data Structures, Hardware Architecture, Databases, Software Engineering, Information Security, Finance, Accounting, Statistics, Discrete Mathematics, Entrepreneurship and Distributed Computing.

CPE Level-Cultura Inglesa SP

2000 - 2010

Gained a relatively deep knowledge and developed advanced written and oral communication skills in English language. Earned multiple Cambrigde certifications (ESOL Examinations).

Technical Course in Software Development – ETEC Aristóteles Ferreira

2009 - 2010

Learned basic programming principles and skills, developed team work and produced an acclaimed RPG player sheet generator as the course's conclusion project.

Certifications	IBM 000-730: DB2 9 Family Fundamentals	2010
	TOEIC	2011 - 2013
	Certificate in Advanced English (CAE) - University of Cambridge ESOL Examination	s 2009
Projects & Interests	GitHub - event-notifications – https://github.com/rodolfo42/event-notifications	April 2013 - May 2013
	Node.js code for a server which receives events and publishes to web-based clients	
	GitHub - guice-provider-sample – https://github.com/rodolfo42/guice-provider-sample	November 2012
	Sample to demonstrate the use of Google Guice Providers	
	GitHub - history-token – https://github.com/rodolfo42/history-token	October 2012
	API simples para lidar com hashes (tudo após o # na URL)	
	GitHub - rodolfo42.github.io – https://github.com/rodolfo42/rodolfo42.github.io	May 2013
	Technical blog	
	GitHub - webdoc – https://github.com/rodolfo42/webdoc Janu	January 2013 - February 2013

A simple web-based documenting system - it's not functional yet $% \label{eq:continuous} % \label{eq:$

Portal para ETEC Alberto Santos Dumont

GitHub-wordpress-etecsd- https://github.com/rodolfo42/wordpress-etecsd

May 2013